<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Niraj Pandkar on Niraj Pandkar</title>
        <link>https://nirajpandkar.github.io/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Niraj Pandkar on Niraj Pandkar</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        
            <language>en</language>
        
        
        
            <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
        
        
            <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 23:18:05 +0530</lastBuildDate>
        
        <atom:link href="https://nirajpandkar.github.io/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
            <item>
                <title>Posts</title>
                <link>https://nirajpandkar.github.io/posts/</link>
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 23:18:05 +0530</pubDate>
                
                <guid>https://nirajpandkar.github.io/posts/</guid>
                <description></description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title></title>
                <link>https://nirajpandkar.github.io/about/</link>
                <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 11:21:13 +0530</pubDate>
                
                <guid>https://nirajpandkar.github.io/about/</guid>
                <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://nirajpandkar.github.io/images/profilepic.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;150&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;Niraj Pandkar&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Niraj! I&#39;m currently working for Riverus, a Legal Tech startup doing some fun stuff. I&#39;ll be documenting my notes/learnings/hiccups, because unlike popular opinion, I love documentation. Don&#39;t @ me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;professional-experience&#34;&gt;Professional Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;riverus-technology-solutions-pvt-ltd-july-2018-till-date&#34;&gt;Riverus Technology Solutions Pvt. Ltd. (July 2018 till date)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Riverus&amp;rdquo; is a software product company in legal domain focused on
applying machine learning to legal research tool. In capacity of data scientist, I report to product manager. I am responsible for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extracting high value analytics from Legal Corpus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;providing reliable and concurrent APIs based on ML models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;building tools using neural networks to solve text-based captchas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;building robust machine learning pipelines for faster throughput&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-year-project&#34;&gt;Final Year Project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding and Analysis of Video and Image Advertisements (July 2018)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed deep learning algorithms to assess the effectiveness of an advertisement and it’s emotional impact on the audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used a public domain dataset – Youtube 8M video dataset and concocted a useful set of features to achieve our goal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We won the best project award in a competition organized by TCS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;personal-projects&#34;&gt;Personal Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nirajpandkar/arvato-customer-segment-identification&#34;&gt;Identifying Customer Segments (Oct 2019)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applied unsupervised learning techniques to identify segments of general population that could be converted into potential customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performed extensive exploratory data analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nirajpandkar/captcha-breaker&#34;&gt;Captcha Solver (Jan 2019)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trained a model using convolution neural networks to solve text-based captchas
eventually helping automate the dependent process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streamlined the process of gathering and annotating data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fine tuned the convolution network to give 95% accuracy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nirajpandkar/ibm-article-recommendation&#34;&gt;Recommendation Engine for IBM (Oct 2019)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on user behavior and social network, a recommendation engine was built
to surface content most likely relevant to a user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge based, content based and collaborative filtering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matrix factorization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Became aware of the cold-start problems in recommendation algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learnt tactics for assessing the effectiveness of recommendation engines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nirajpandkar/sparkify&#34;&gt;Sparkify (March 2019)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predicting whether a customer is going to churn based on his/her behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data provided is a simulated data from an imaginary streaming service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluation of the predictive model was done using F1 score.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;professional-projects&#34;&gt;Professional Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optical Character Recognition for PDF documents (Aug 18 - Jan 19)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built an OCR pipeline for converting scanned images to PDF for further
processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used Google’s tesseract for converting scanned image into text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed a tool for removing watermarks from the PDF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keyphrase Clustering (Nov 18- Jan 19)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyphrase clustering is used for auto-complete feature while searching for
Legal cases and indirectly for identifying similar cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trained a Word2Vec model on the legal corpus to make the machine
understand Legal context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used the trained model to cluster key phrases into 800 buckets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built a tool to categorize the incoming new key phrases into the said
buckets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue Sentence Similarity (Nov 18 - Jan 19)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked on a proof of concept to achieve issue sentence similarity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created sentence embeddings using Term Frequency and Inverse Document
Frequency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fine-tuned the sentence embeddings to determine similar issue sentences and
achieved a satisfactory result&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Named Entity Recognition (May 19 - Jul 19)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NER model is used to extract valuable information from text like Sections, Acts,
Judges and Lawyers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trained NER using Stanford’s CRF algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fine-tune the hyper-parameters to suit the corporate needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cocurricular-activities&#34;&gt;Co-curricular activities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organized a workshop for 50+ students which gives them basic overview of how
to use Tensorflow using a toy project – Digit Recognizer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed a website using PHP, HTML and CSS for a Rubik’s Cube Club that I had
founded in my second year for organizing competitions and workshops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smart India Hacakthon (Qualified for the finals)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Infosys Hackathon (Second runners-up)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
